<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nelo | Web Developer &amp; UI Designer</title>
    <description>I work remotely with startups and agencies around the world to transform ideas into great products for web and mobile.</description>
    <link>http://nelo.ph//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://nelo.ph//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 04:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 04:32:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-is-my-first-post-ever&quot;&gt;This is my first post ever.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been planning to launch a blog since forever mainly to document learnings, improve my writing skills and keep myself accountable. To you, my dear Internet friend, welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;year-in-review&quot;&gt;2016 year in review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before planning the future, I wanted to look back on the things I’ve accomplished last year to have a good idea of where I’m currently at. Though last year was terrible &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/search?q=%232016ed&quot;&gt;for a lot of reasons&lt;/a&gt;, it was a great year for me over-all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been my second year working remotely and during my first few months, I really struggled with isolation. Last year, I became a member of two awesome communities: &lt;a href=&quot;//upmountaineers.org&quot;&gt;UP Mountaineers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;//x-team.com&quot;&gt;X-Team&lt;/a&gt;.
I learned a lot from these groups and also finally started to feel a sense of belongingness again. Becoming a member of these groups improved my communication, accountability, and self-confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;specialization-and-career-growth&quot;&gt;Specialization and Career Growth&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working independently, my career growth is ultimately dependent on my motivation to improve myself.
Coming from being a full-stack developer, I decided to narrow my focus on UI design and front-end development: fields which I think I can deliver most value to my clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mastered ReactJS (using it since 2014), established a design workflow using Sketch, Invision, and Zeplin, launched my new web portfolio, worked on an Electron project, and managed to make major contributions to 7 projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also last year that I’ve established a solid work routine that works for me. This is crucial for freelancers tasked to &lt;em&gt;manage their own time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;travel-and-adventure&quot;&gt;Travel and Adventure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a &lt;a href=&quot;//www.youtube.com/watch?v=TP0t9ahizNk&quot;&gt;four-day hike&lt;/a&gt; with the UP mountaineers, climbed a couple of mountains after that, backpacked across Indochina (Vietnam, Cambodia, and Thailand), and finished The North Face’s Half Trail Marathon (22 km).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-it-on-2017&quot;&gt;Bring it on 2017!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the good things that I started last year, I wanted to keep consistent this year. After all, it’s all about the process, not the end-goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;become-more-active-in-the-community&quot;&gt;Become more active in the community&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last quarter of last year, I became too focused on my work that I became inactive with the communities that I belong to and started to feel a lot of isolation again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;back-to-generalization-maybe&quot;&gt;Back to Generalization, maybe?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my goals in the next 2 years is to be able to create a passive income stream through a digital product. I wanted to learn the technologies that enable me to rollout product ideas as quickly as possible for market testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will still be focusing on UI design and front-end development but give a conscious effort towards learning back-end and dev ops technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;more-travel&quot;&gt;More travel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to spend more time travelling than ever before but would like to prioritize local travel. The Philippines has 81 provinces with each offering a variety of culture and adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;growth-through-reading&quot;&gt;Growth through reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself reading a lot (Reddit, Medium, etc) but rarely learning something that I could carry around for years.
I commit to reading at least 12 books this year and will surely share its gists on this blog. If you have any recommendations, please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let this year be a year of growth and consistency. To a great year ahead! 🍻&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://nelo.ph//hello-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nelo.ph//hello-world</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
